Leopold Haller

 ♦ Berkeley, California
 ☑ leopoldhaller@gmail.com
 ७ (510) 292-1849
 in leopoldhaller
 ♀ lcrh

Summary

I am a **research engineer** and **technical leader** with 10+ years of professional experience in software engineering, ML engineering and research. I am seeking a challenging IC role on the cutting-edge of AI research or product development as part of a capable team. My academic background is in automated reasoning and static analysis, and I am particularly interested in the intersection of **machine learning**, **automated reasoning** and **program search**.

Key skills: ML, RL, generative AI agents, software engineering, greenfield AI product development, automated reasoning, SAT/SMT, formal verification, theorem proving.

Experience

Cofounder & Chief Research Officer, Agentic - San Francisco, CA

June 2021 – Dec 2024

- Led research team of 3 on interactive training of video game AI for game testing.
- Developed novel techniques in imitation learning and RL to build a product that allows ML-naive game developers to train useful agents on interactive time-scales.
- Initiated a company pivot from ML to Voyager-style **LLM-based code generation** for video game AI (GDC trailer **Z**), owning the project from prototype through deployment.
- Developed an open-source framework for generative software, **enact** (github 🗹) to serve as the basis of our agents stack.
- Key contributor to all aspects of development, including backend infrastructure, research, UX and product.

Senior Software Engineer, Google - San Francisco, CA

May 2015 – June 2021

- Google Brain Kernel Product Incubator (2019): Core contributor on ML-driven video game agents. Designed and developed DAgger-style training methodology and built initial service architecture for continuous live training. (patent , OSS repo)
- Area120 Chatbase (2017): Trained early LLMs (BERT) for chat applications. My work was central to our team securing the first successful exit from the Area120 incubator program. Rebuilt live data-analytics backend of our chat telemetry platform.
- Security & Privacy (2015): Developed large-scale static code analyses for detecting privacy concerns.

Member of Consulting Staff, Cadence Design Systems – Berkeley, CA

Dec 2012 - May 2015

• Developed SAT/SMT-based algorithms for **formal verification** of hardware designs.

Research Intern, Microsoft – Cambridge, UK

May 2009 – Aug 2009

Mar 2023 – present

• Developed FPGA-based constraint propagation accelerator for SAT solving.

Education

University of Oxford, PhD in Computer Science, Formal Methods (dissertation ☑) • 14 conference & journal publications ☑ in formal methods	2008 – 2013
Vienna University of Technology, MSc in Computational Intelligence	2006 – 2008
Johannes Kepler University Linz, BSc in Computer Science	2003 – 2006

Advisorships

Advisor, Newlife.ai May 2024 – present

• Advising on blockchain protocols for distributed AI agents.

Advisor, Standard Deviants

• Advising on generative AI for interactive story-telling.

Technologies

Main languages & Frameworks: Python, C++, tf, tflite, jax, numpy, pandas, Lean, Go

Tech: gcloud, kubernetes, postgres, spanner, dremel/bigquery, grpc, protobuf

OSS Projects

enact - A framework for generative software.

github/agentic-ai 🗹

- Framework for managing execution of scaffolding programs: telemetry, serialization, record / replay.
- Example: Generic MCTS implementation for scaffolding programs (notebook)

threaded-async

github/agentic-ai 🗹

• Helper library used internally at agentic to coordinate asynchronous AI-generated python code with game engines via a task system.

Falken

github/google-research <a>™

• Python service & C++ SDK for DAgger-style training of video game AI, built as part of a Google team.